<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on SerresTech - The Technology community of Serres, Greece</title>
    <link>https://www.serrestech.gr/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on SerresTech - The Technology community of Serres, Greece</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.serrestech.gr/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hackathon 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.serrestech.gr/blog/2019/05/hackathon-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.serrestech.gr/blog/2019/05/hackathon-2019/</guid>
      <description>Hackathon Serres 2019 - Web Attack Mining Η τεχνολογική κοινότητα Σερρών SerresTech.gr και το Πρόγραμμα Μεταπτυχιακών Σπουδών στην Εφαρμοσμένη Πληροφορική του Τμήματος Μηχανικών Πληροφορικής, ΤΕΙ Κεντρικής Μακεδονίας (Σερρών) διοργανώνουν το 4ο Hackathon Serres με θέμα &amp;ldquo;Web Attack Mining&amp;ldquo; το Σάββατο 18 και την Κυριακή 19 Μαΐου 2019.
Μετά την επιτυχή διοργάνωση του 2018 ο διαγωνισμός επαναλαμβάνεται αυτή τη φορά με την εμπειρία 3 πλέον διοργανώσεων (2016, 2017, 2018) καθώς και με την υποστήριξη περισσότερων φορέων και εταιρειών.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ΑΝΟΙΚΤΗ ΕΠΙΣΤΟΛΗ ΠΡΟΣ ΥΠΟΨΗΦΙΟΥΣ (ΠΕΡΙΦΕΡΕΙΑΡΧΕΣ, ΑΝΤΙΠΕΡΙΦΕΡΕΙΑΡΧΕΣ ΚΑΙ ΔΗΜΑΡΧΟΥΣ)</title>
      <link>https://www.serrestech.gr/blog/2019/02/election-2019-open-letter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.serrestech.gr/blog/2019/02/election-2019-open-letter/</guid>
      <description>ΑΝΟΙΚΤΗ ΕΠΙΣΤΟΛΗ ΠΡΟΣ ΥΠΟΨΗΦΙΟΥΣ 2019 (ΠΕΡΙΦΕΡΕΙΑΡΧΕΣ, ΑΝΤΙΠΕΡΙΦΕΡΕΙΑΡΧΕΣ ΚΑΙ ΔΗΜΑΡΧΟΥΣ) Υπογραφω την Ανοιχτη Επιστολη
Η κοινότητα SerresTech (www.serrestech.gr) είναι μια ζωντανή κοινότητα εθελοντών, που αριθμεί τη συγκεκριμένη στιγμή πάνω από 280 άτομα και έχει ως κύριο στόχο την διαμόρφωση ενός περιβάλλοντος ευνοϊκού για την εξέλιξη της τεχνολογίας και ειδικότερα της βιομηχανίας λογισμικού στην περιοχή μας.
Όμως η διαμόρφωση ενός ευνοϊκού για την τεχνολογία περιβάλλοντος περνά και μέσα από αποφάσεις και της τοπικής (δημοτικής και περιφερειακής) διοίκησης.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ζητάμε εθελοντές! We are looking for volunteers!</title>
      <link>https://www.serrestech.gr/blog/2019/02/2019-02-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 11:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.serrestech.gr/blog/2019/02/2019-02-20/</guid>
      <description>Η κοινότητά μας στηρίζεται κατά κόρον στους εθελοντές. Σκεφτήκαμε ότι θα ήταν χρήσιμο να αναθέσουμε σε άτομα από την κοινότητά μας εργασίες που θα βοηθήσουν στο να έχουμε καλύτερα αποτελέσματα τόσο στη διάχυση των προσπαθειών μας όσο και στην ενημέρωση και εκπαίδευση των μελών μας.
Για το λόγο αυτό, ζητάμε
1-3 video directors
Οι εθελοντές αυτοί θα επιφορτιστούν με τη διαχείριση των βίντεο που δημιουργούνται κατά τη διάρκεια των παρουσιάσεων που κάνουμε.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Official, we now run on Netlify!</title>
      <link>https://www.serrestech.gr/blog/2019/01/2019-01-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 11:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.serrestech.gr/blog/2019/01/2019-01-30/</guid>
      <description>After two months live we finally found out some time to integrate our Hugo built website with Netlify CMS as also as serve the website from Netlify.
So, yes, we are proud of it and we are very happy to be able to have an Admin Dashboard to create blog posts.
Stay tuned, we may have a presentation on our Meetup about Netlify, Hugo and Jamstack soon!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mini conference: Java Security, Testing practices and Team dynamics</title>
      <link>https://www.serrestech.gr/blog/2019/01/4th-meetup-jan-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.serrestech.gr/blog/2019/01/4th-meetup-jan-2019/</guid>
      <description>Get the official Poster
We are welcoming 2019 with a mini-conference and presenters from three different countries and two different continents!
This time we will host three different talks in a mini conference meetup on Saturday:
 A talk on Java security architecture, by Martin Toshev, member of the Bulgarian Java User Group and Software Architect at Resolve Systems Agile Testing Practices, with examples on Java, by John Pourdanis, Test Automation Engineer, ISTQB Certified Tester working at Pheron LTD (SchooX group).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mini conference: Java Security, Testing practices and Team dynamics</title>
      <link>https://www.serrestech.gr/blog/2019/01/4th-meetup-jan-20190/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.serrestech.gr/blog/2019/01/4th-meetup-jan-20190/</guid>
      <description>Get the official Poster
We are welcoming 2019 with a mini-conference and presenters from three different countries and two different continents!
This time we will host three different talks in a mini conference meetup on Saturday:
 A talk on Java security architecture, by Martin Toshev, member of the Bulgarian Java User Group and Software Architect at Resolve Systems Agile Testing Practices, with examples on Java, by John Pourdanis, Test Automation Engineer, ISTQB Certified Tester working at Pheron LTD (SchooX group).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software development at CERN</title>
      <link>https://www.serrestech.gr/blog/2018/12/3rd-meetup-dec-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.serrestech.gr/blog/2018/12/3rd-meetup-dec-2018/</guid>
      <description>Get the official Poster
This presentation will provide an introduction to CERN and its operations, focusing on software development and the various opportunities available.
Afterward there will be a dive into the development process which is followed on the applications, presenting the various technologies, frameworks and practices followed.
Moreover we will dive into the Accelerators Logging Service one of the major big data projects at CERN and will demonstrate data analysis with Spark on Hadoop (Jupyter).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s talk about event based microservices</title>
      <link>https://www.serrestech.gr/blog/2018/11/2nd-meetup-nov-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.serrestech.gr/blog/2018/11/2nd-meetup-nov-2018/</guid>
      <description>Στο τελευταίο, πριν το VoxxedDays, meetup θα φιλοξενήσουμε το Γρηγόρη Γρηγοριάδη, software architect στην itsaur!
Τα microservices συζητιούνται όλο και περισσότερο τα τελευταία χρόνια ως πανάκεια σε όλα τα προβλήματα. Πόσο αλήθεια είναι αυτό. Ο κος Γρηγοριάδης θα μας αναφέρει τις εμπειρίες του από πραγματικά έργα λογισμικού, θα μιλήσει για τα &amp;ldquo;πρέπει&amp;rdquo; και &amp;ldquo;δεν πρέπει&amp;rdquo; αυτής της προσέγγισης!
Ημερομηνία: Παρασκευή, 16 Νοεμβρίου 2018 Ώρα: 18:00 - 21:00 Χώρος: ΤΕΙ Κεντρικής Μακεδονίας - Σέρρες (Τέρμα Μαγνησίας) Κτίριο Πληροφορικής, Αίθουσα 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s talk about Arch Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.serrestech.gr/blog/2018/10/1st-meetup-oct-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.serrestech.gr/blog/2018/10/1st-meetup-oct-2018/</guid>
      <description>Είναι η πρώτη συνάντησή μας για τη νέα χρόνια. Θα καλωσορίσουμε τα νέα μέλη, θα παρουσιάσουμε το πλάνο μας για τη νέα χρονιά, το πλούσιο πρόγραμμα διαλέξεων που ετοιμάζουμε και θα συζητήσουμε για το πως θα οργανώσουμε ένα καλύτερο hackathon!
Αλλά δε θα κάνουμε μόνο αυτό. Το μέλος μας Δημήτρης Κιζιρίδης θα μιλήσει για τη διανομή Arch Linux!
Πιο συγκεκριμένα θα γίνει demo εγκατάσταση και χρήση του Arch Linux σε VM περιβάλλον, καθώς και παρουσίαση διάφορων Shell, εισαγωγή στα unit files και εξήγηση του systemd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Speakers 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.serrestech.gr/blog/2018/09/call-for-speakers-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.serrestech.gr/blog/2018/09/call-for-speakers-2019/</guid>
      <description>If you are interested to make a presentation, a workshop or any other talk related to our community interests feel free to submit the &amp;ldquo;Call for Speakers&amp;rdquo; form here.
The submissions will help us organize better our meetups.
 The events take place in the city of Serres in Greece mostly in the evening hours. We are open to any dates and topics. Professional speakers from abroad may have extra benefits such as lanches, accomodation, travel tickets etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hackathon 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.serrestech.gr/blog/2018/03/hackathon-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.serrestech.gr/blog/2018/03/hackathon-2018/</guid>
      <description>Hackathon 2018 announcement As every year SerresTech community is going to organize a 2 days Hackathon open to everyone.
Last year 2017 Hackathon Serres 2.0 is also archived for reference
A dedicated website for the 2018 hackathon has been created. Join it or share the news!
Hackathon Serres No3 - 2018</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>